markdown.com 2014-04-10

# Privacy Policy

MERCURY DIGITAL LABS LLC d/b/a Markdown (“Markdown”) realizes the importance of respecting and protecting your privacy.

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) discloses the information that Markdown gathers on the web site MARKDOWN.COM that Markdown owns (the “Site”), as well as ways in which Markdown processes and, sometimes, shares such information and how you can correct or change that information. The Site also includes versions designed for browsing on mobile devices and the use of such devices is governed by this Privacy Policy as well.

Except where otherwise expressly indicated herein or on the Site, this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected on the Site and does not apply to information collected outside of the Site. Before using or submitting information to the Site please review this Privacy Policy carefully.

Certain areas of the Site contain information intended only for users who create an account, join or otherwise register to use any of the Site (“Registered Users”) and Markdown reserves the right to limit these areas to Registered Users. This Privacy Policy addresses Markdown’s privacy practices relating to general use of the Site, as well as use of the Site by Registered Users.

**B. Information Markdown Collects**

Markdown collects the following types of information from users of the Site:

**1\. Personally Identifiable Information**

Markdown may receive and store any information that you enter on the Site or provide to Markdown in any other way that would allow Markdown to identify you or contact you (collectively “Personally Identifiable Information”). The Personally Identifiable Information that you provide will be used by Markdown only in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Examples of Personally Identifiable Information Markdown may collect from you and use are:

  * your name, address, phone number(s), e-mail address, date of birth, nationality and gender if you are a Registered User or are otherwise asked to provide such information;
  * the e-mail addresses of those who post comments, stories, photos, videos and other content on the Site;
  * the names and e-mail addresses of those who communicate with Markdown by e-mail;
  * the names, e-mail addresses and zip code of those who specifically opt-in to special offers;
  * the payment and identity verification information, such as credit card number, social security number (or comparable national identifier) and driver’s license number when needed for payment information in connection with a purchase made through the Site;
  * information about your family or friends, including, but not limited to, the name, address, phone number(s), e-mail address, date of birth, nationality and gender of any family member or friend, that you provide in connection with your use of the Site or any feature thereof;
  * information you provide about yourself, including, but not limited to your name, e-mail address, date of birth, nationality, gender and preferences, that you provide when you register; and
  * information you provide about yourself when you post to the Site.
  * if you choose to interact with the Site using Facebook Connect, we may collect information from your Facebook account through an automated connection to Facebook.

You can choose not to provide Markdown with certain Personally Identifiable Information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many features of the Site, such as posting comments, registering to use certain restricted areas of the Site, participating in Markdown’s online community, entering a sweepstakes or contest on the Site or through Facebook, participating in various promotional opportunities or receiving e-mail alerts or newsletters.

**2\. Automatic Information**

(a) Collected By Markdown

Markdown may receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with Markdown through the Site. We automatically receive and record your browser information, operating system information, IP address, cookie information and the page you requested. This information will not be stored in a manner that is personally identifiable with you and may include the following:

**(1) Aggregate Information**

In connection with your visit to the Site, Markdown may automatically collect usage information, such as the numbers and frequency of users and their characteristics and information about similar groups of users, such as parents, certain age groups or users that live in a particular geographical area. This data is only used in the aggregate as a statistical measure and not in a manner that would identify you personally. Aggregate information generally is collected through the use of cookies and Web Beacons as discussed below.

**(2) Cookies**

Markdown uses “cookies” to help you access and navigate the Site more efficiently and to statistically monitor how many people are using the Site. A “cookie” is a small file or tool stored on your hard drive containing information that allows Markdown to deliver customized information to you. If you become a Registered User, Markdown may use cookies to store your e-mail address, user name, preferences and password so that Markdown can identify you when you return to the Site, track your use of the Site and customize the Site for you. You may set your browser to notify you of or decline the receipt of cookies. Certain features of the Site may not, however, function properly or be available if your browser is configured to disable cookies.

Markdown uses both “session” and “persistent” cookies on the Site. Session cookies are temporary bits of information that are erased once you exit your web browser or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies are more permanent bits of information that are placed on the hard drive of your computer and stay there unless you delete the cookie. Persistent cookies store information on your computer for a number of reasons, such as retrieving certain information you have previously provided (i.e., username and password), helping to determine what areas of the Site you find most valuable and customizing the Site based on your preferences on an ongoing basis.

Many companies offer programs that help you to visit web sites anonymously. While Markdown will not be able to provide you with a personalized experience if Markdown cannot recognize you, Markdown wants you to be aware that these programs are available.

**(3) Web Beacons**

During your use of the Site, you may encounter Web Beacons, which may come from Markdown or from third parties that advertise or provide content on the Site. A “Web Beacon” (sometimes also called a “web bug” or “clear gif”) is a small graphic image in a web page, a web-based document or an e-mail message that generally allows the party that set the Web Beacon to monitor certain information about the viewer of the web page, web-based document or e-mail message and may allow access to certain cookies. Web Beacons are usually invisible to the user because they are very small (generally 1-by-1 pixel). In general, however, any electronic image viewed as part of a web page, including an advertisement, can act as a Web Beacon. Web Beacons on the Site typically collect the URL of the page from which the Web Beacon originates, the type of browser requesting the Web Beacon, the IP address of the computer to which the Web Beacon is sent and the time that the Web Beacon was viewed. Certain Web Beacons used by third party advertisers or content providers may collect information that allows such third parties to determine how many people are viewing and/or clicking on certain advertisements or viewing certain content for purposes of helping these parties serve and manage their advertisements and content. These Web Beacons do not collect or store Personally Identifiable Information but they may, however, be used in conjunction with cookies to identify certain aggregate information about users.

**(4) E-mail Communications**

When you send an e-mail to Markdown, either through the button on the Site or otherwise, Markdown may retain your e-mail address and the contents of the e-mail that you send. If you want to keep the information in your e-mail(s) or posting(s) private or proprietary, please do not send such information in an e-mail or otherwise post such information to Markdown. To help Markdown make its e-mails more interesting and helpful, Markdown also may receive a confirmation when you open an e-mail from Markdown if your computer supports this type of program.

**(b) Information Collected by Third Parties**

Markdown may allow third parties to display advertisements on the Site. Markdown and these third parties may use tracking technologies, such as cookies and Web Beacons, to collect information about users who view or interact with these advertisements and connect to the Site.

**(1) Ad Servers**

Markdown, its partners and/or advertisers may use third party ad servers to serve or present the ads that appear on the Site and to conduct research about the advertisements. Any of these ad servers may collect non-personal information, such as your browser, operating system, date/time of viewing, IP address and clickstream data. Markdown cannot control the activities of such advertisers or web sites. PLEASE NOTE THAT THIS POLICY DOES NOT COVER THE COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION BY SUCH AD SERVERS.

**C. How Markdown Uses Information**

When you provide Markdown with your Personally Identifiable Information, Markdown may use it to manage Markdown’s registry of Registered Users, facilitate communication between Markdown and you and/or between Registered Users of the Site, notify you of features or special events and provide you with other information Markdown feels may be of interest to you. Markdown also uses information collected to customize, analyze, adjust and improve the Site to meet Markdown’s users’ needs and expectations. Markdown also may use the information to oversee adherence to Markdown’s Community Guidelines which are provided in the Terms of Use for the Site to enforce Markdown’s agreements with you, to prevent fraud and other prohibited or illegal activities and for other legally permissible purposes. These uses of your Personally Identifiable Information may include, without limitation, the following:

**1\. Public Areas**

The Site feature groups, discussions, member profiles, comment areas, blogs and similar areas where users can share information about themselves and their opinions, as well as post questions (“Public Areas”). Other visitors to the Site may view information posted in Public Areas. Further, Markdown may include all or a portion of the information posted in Public Areas in the newsletters described in this Privacy Policy. By using the Public Areas, you hereby acknowledge and agree that any information you share in a Public Area (including, without limitation, Personally Identifiable Information) is available to the public. Information you post to a Public Area may be viewed, accessed, or collected by, or disclosed to, third parties and may be used by others in ways neither you nor Markdown are able to control or predict, including, without limitation, to contact you for unauthorized purposes.

The Site offers the ability to forward content to another person via e-mail. If you use this service, Markdown will use the recipient’s e-mail address in order to send the content and Markdown will also ask for your e-mail address Markdown does not use the recipient’s e-mail address for any other purpose unless the recipient gives Markdown permission to do so.

**2\. Registered User Areas**

If you have access to certain areas of the Site because you are a Registered User (“Registered User Areas”), the Registered User Areas may contain groups, discussions, member profiles, comment areas, blogs and similar areas where Registered Users can share information about themselves and their opinions, as well as post questions. Information you post to a Registered User Area may be viewed, accessed, or collected by, or disclosed to, other Registered Users and may be used by other Registered Users in ways neither you nor Markdown are able to control or predict, including, without limitation, disclosure of your information to the public or to contact you for unauthorized purposes. Markdown uses the Personally Identifiable Information you provide when registering to become a Registered User to send you Markdown publications, information about Registered User benefits and special offers, features included in the Registered User Areas and other information that Markdown believes is relevant and useful to its Registered Users. By using the Registered User Areas, you hereby acknowledge and agree that any information you share in a Registered User Area (including, without limitation, Personally Identifiable Information) is available to other Registered Users and to Markdown for use as provided herein.

**3\. Profiles**

If you register to become a Registered User of the Site, the information that you provide to Markdown may be stored in one or more profiles. These profiles, or a portion thereof, may be viewed by other Users of the Site, including, but not limited to those who are not Registered Users of the Site.

**4\. E-Newsletters**

If you register at any of the Site, you may choose to receive a newsletter via e-mail from Markdown which may include information such as highlights from different areas on the Site and information about new features. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any e-mail newsletter sent to you and following the instructions. You also may unsubscribe at any time by logging in to the applicable Site where you created your profile and changing your preferences.

**5\. Aggregate Information**

The aggregate information collected by Markdown also is used to create profiles of the audience for the Site that include anonymous statistical demographic information but no Personally Identifiable Information. This aggregated information is used to, among other things, determine trends and needs and supply market research to potential advertisers and partners to help them understand the Site’s audiences. For example, Markdown may create a report that tells advertisers that thirty percent of Markdown’s Registered Users are males under forty years, so that they can determine which of their products or services are most appropriate for Markdown’s Registered Users.

**D. With Whom Markdown Shares Information**

Markdown reserves the right to use your Personally Identifiable Information to send you periodic e-mailings with information on new products and services, updates to Markdown’s Site or upcoming events.

If you “opt in” to receive information about identified advertisers or their services or products, Markdown may share your Personally Identifiable Information with them. If you have questions about how these companies use your Personally Identifiable Information, Markdown encourages you to review and understand their respective privacy policies. You may at any time “opt out” of having your Personally Identifiable Information as part of Markdown’s marketing mailing list or otherwise (see “Opting Out” below).

From time to time, in Markdown’s sole discretion, Markdown may use your Personally Identifiable Information to send you important administrative information regarding the Site and related services or changes to Markdown’s Terms and policies. Because this information may be important to your use of the Site and related services, you may not opt out of receiving such communications.

If you interact with the Site through Facebook, Markdown may share information with Facebook and other users of Facebook.

**1\. Fulfillment of Services**

Markdown may retain other companies and individuals to perform functions consistent with Markdown’s Privacy Policy on Markdown’s behalf. Examples include customer support specialists, web hosting companies, fulfillment companies (e.g., companies that fill product orders or coordinate mailings), data analysis firms and e-mail service providers.

**2\. Compliance with Law and Fraud Protection**

Markdown may disclose any information, including without limitation Personally Identifiable Information, that Markdown deems necessary, in its sole discretion and without your prior permission, to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request. Markdown also may exchange information, including without limitation Personally Identifiable Information, with other companies and organizations for credit fraud protection, risk reduction and related activities or to protect the rights, property of safety of Markdown and its agents, employees or affiliates or others. Markdown reserves the right to disclose a user’s Personally Identifiable Information if Markdown believes the user is in violation of Markdown’s Terms of Use, even without a subpoena, warrant or other court order.

**3\. Sale or Transfer of Information**

In the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, dissolution or sale or transfer of substantially all of the assets of Markdown or the Site, personal Information and/or other information collected about you from the Site may be sold, assigned or transferred to the party acquiring all or substantially all of the equity and/or assets of Markdown or the Site in order to permit the party to continue the operation of the Site, including the Registered User Areas. Subject to your ability to opt-out, you consent to the sale and transfer of your information as described in this paragraph.

**4\. Accessing, Updating or Deleting your Personally Identifiable Information**

If you are a Registered User and would like to review, update or delete your profile, please log in to and select the profile in which you would like to review, modify or delete information (i.e., the Personally Identifiable Information you have provided to us).

**5\. Opting Out**

Markdown respects the privacy of your Personally Identifiable Information. If you tell Markdown that you do not wish to have this information used as a basis for further contact with you, Markdown will respect your wishes. You also may choose not to provide Markdown with certain information, but that may result in you being unable to use certain features of the Site.

You may instruct Markdown to stop sending you certain promotional materials (e.g., e-mail messages, newsletters, postcards and letters) by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in those materials. Markdown may, however, continue to contact you to provide service to your account. Please note that if you use more than one name or e-mail address when communicating with Markdown or participating on the Site, you may continue to receive communications from Markdown to any name and/or e-mail address which you have not specified in your opt-out request.

Markdown provides you with the following options for removing your Personally Identifiable Information from Markdown’s database for marketing purposes:

a. You can send an email to [support@markdown.com](mailto:support@markdown.com); or

b. You can send mail to the following postal address:

Markdown, 1133 Avenue of the Americas, 34th Floor, New York, New York 10036

E. Important Disclosures, Practices and Contact Information

**1\. Third Party Links**

The Site contains links to third-party web sites. Please be aware that Markdown cannot control and is not responsible for the information collection practices of such web sites, which may differ from those of Markdown. Markdown encourages you to review and understand the privacy policies of these web sites before providing any information to them.

**2\. Interactive Features**

The Site may make groups, discussions, chat rooms, forums and message boards available to users (see “Public Areas” described above). While you are required to register with the Site to post in these areas, you are not required to provide any Personally Identifiable Information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post Personally Identifiable Information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. Markdown cannot ensure the security of any information that you choose to make public in a group, discussion, chat room, forum or message board. Also, Markdown cannot ensure that parties who have access to such Personally Identifiable Information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose Personally Identifiable Information in these areas.

**3\. Data Security**

Markdown maintains a variety of commercially reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards designed to protect your Personally Identifiable Information from unauthorized access and disclosure. For example, Markdown uses accepted tools and techniques to protect against unauthorized access to Markdown’s systems. You should be aware that Markdown has no control over the security of other sites on the Internet that you might visit or with which you might interact even when a link may appear to another site from one of the Site.

Markdown wants you to feel confident using the Site but no system can be completely secure. Therefore, although Markdown takes steps to secure your information, Markdown does not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information, searches or other communications will always remain secure.

**4\. Children**

The Site is a general audience site and is not intended for children under 13. Markdown requires that only persons 13 years of age or older use any of the Site. By using the Site, you hereby represent that you are at least 13 years old. Markdown does not knowingly market to, solicit information, accept service or collect information from children under the age of 13. If Markdown becomes aware that it inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of 13 on the Site, Markdown will delete the information from its records.

**5\. Changes to this Privacy Policy**

At any time without prior notice, Markdown may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in Markdown’s practices. When Markdown posts changes to this Privacy Policy, Markdown will revise the “Last Updated” date at the top of this page. Markdown encourages you to bookmark this Privacy Policy and to periodically review it to inform yourself of changes to it or any of Markdown’s other policies. Any changes to Markdown’s Privacy Policy will become effective upon Markdown’s posting of the updated policy. Use of the Site constitutes your acceptance of the terms of this Privacy Policy then in effect.

**6\. California Privacy Rights Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83**

If you are a resident of California (“California Users”), in addition to the rights set forth in this Privacy Policy, you generally have the right to request information from Markdown regarding the manner in which Markdown shares certain categories of Personally Identifiable Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

Under the law, however, a business is not required to provide this information if it adopts and discloses to the public (in its privacy policy) a policy of not disclosing customer’s personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless the customer first affirmatively agrees to the disclosure, as long as the business maintains and discloses this policy. Rather, the business may comply with the law by notifying California Users of their rights to prevent disclosure of personal information and providing a cost free means to exercise that right.

Please note that whenever you opt in to receive future communications from a third party, your information will be subject to the third party’s privacy policy. If you later decide that you do not want that third party to use your information, you will need to contact the third party directly, as Markdown has no control over how third parties use information. You should always review the privacy policy of any party that collects your information to determine how it will handle your information.

Please note that Markdown is only required to respond to one request per customer each year. Markdown is not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this e-mail address: support@markdown.com.

**7\. Users From Outside the United States**

By visiting the Site, submitting information or using any of Markdown’s products or services, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy and consent to having your data transferred to and processed in the United States. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use Markdown’s Site.

The Site is controlled and operated by Markdown from the United States. Markdown does not represent or warrant that the Site, or any part thereof, are appropriate or available for use in any particular jurisdiction. Those who choose to access the Site do so on their own initiative and at their own risk, and are responsible for complying with all local laws, rules and regulations. You also are subject to United States export controls in connection with your use of the Site and/or services related thereto and are responsible for any violations of such controls, including, without limitation, any United States embargoes or other federal rules and regulations restricting exports. Markdown may limit the availability of the Site, in whole or in part, to any person, geographic area or jurisdiction that Markdown chooses, at any time and in Markdown’s sole discretion.

**8\. No Rights of Third Parties**

This Privacy Policy does not create rights enforceable by third parties.

9\. Contacting Markdown

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the Site or your dealings with us, please feel free to contact Markdown at:

  * Markdown, 1133 Avenue of the Americas, 34th Floor, New York, New York 10036,
  * Email: [support@markdown.com](mailto:support@markdown.com)
